hello and welcome back to new everyday
こんにちは、そして新しい毎日へようこそ
I'm Carrie and today on our show we have
私はキャリーです、そして今日私達のショーで私達は持っています
a very special guest Rob Webb who
とても特別なゲストRob Webb
happens to be my dad and he's going to
たまたま私のお父さんになって
be talking about the authority of the
の権威について話している
Bible
聖書
you've got mad skills now hone them
あなたは狂ったスキルを手に入れました
learn new skills or improve your
新しいスキルを習得するか、あなたの能力を向上させる
existing ones with online video
オンラインビデオのある既存のもの
tutorials and training from Linda calm
Lindaからのチュートリアルとトレーニング
through our special link at cat five dot
猫5ドットで私たちの特別なリンクを介して
TV / Linda learn software technology
TV / Lindaがソフトウェア技術を学ぶ
creative and business skills you can use
あなたが使うことができる創造的でビジネススキル
today to help you achieve your
今日あなたがあなたの 達成 を助ける ために
professional goals join today and start
今日からプロのゴールに参加してスタート
learning will give you this chance to
学ぶことはあなたにこの機会を与えるでしょう
try it absolutely free with unlimited
無制限で絶対に無料で試す
access to all of the courses sign up now
今すぐ 申し込む すべての コースへのアクセス
for free cat5 dot TV / linda
無料cat5 dot TV /リンダ用
well welcome back again we have a
よく私たちが持って再び戻って歓迎
special guest here Rob web my dad thanks
特別ゲストはこちらRob web私のお父さん感謝
dad come on the show my pleasure how are
お父さんは私の喜びはどのようにショーに来ます
you I'm fine good to be here thank you
あなたはここにいられて嬉しいよ
when I first asked you to come on the
私が最初にあなた に来るように頼んだとき
show you suggested the topic of the
のトピックを提案した
authority of the Bible and why did that
聖書の権威とその理由
come to your mind as something that you
あなたの何かとしてあなたの頭の中に来る
wanted to share with others well it's
他の人とうまく共有したい
been my experience when I've gone to
私が行ったときの経験
share the gospel and I speak of of the
福音を分かち合うと
Lord and I referenced the Bible it had
主と私はそれが持っていた聖書を参照しました
its happened where people were
それは人々がいたところで起こった
questioning well that's fine for you you
よく質問することはあなたのために結構です
believe in the Bible you have your
聖書を信じる
source I have my own and so I think we
情報源私は自分のものを持っているので、私たちは
need to have a way and a reason why
方法と理由が必要
people would trust the authority
人々は権威を信頼する
description we need to have those
説明が必要です
answers now not everyone would have that
答えは今誰もがそれを持っているというわけではない
question but but when it comes up and I
質問が、それが出てくると私は
think in our own hearts we need to
自分の心で考える必要がある
understand who we are and why is the
私たちが誰なのか、なぜ
Bible is our Authority and be able to
聖書は私たちの権威であるとのことができるように
give that evidence when we were asked so
私たち が求められた ときにその証拠を与える
I think it's important to validate what
何を検証することが重要だと思います
we're saying the Lord has given us
私たちは主が私たちに与えて下さったと言っています
evidence and the lengths that he's gone
彼が行った証拠と長さ
to to get his word to us is absolutely
私たちに彼の言葉を届けることは絶対に
phenomenal and the depth of the troops
驚異的かつ軍隊の深さ
there and the evidence and so it's
そこにそして証拠そしてそうそれはあります
exciting to to to see what God has done
神がなさったことを見ることにわくわくします
and the lengths he's gone to and to be
そして彼が行ったことのある長さ
able to share that and give evidence in
それを共有し、証拠を提供することができる
support for the gospel and your
福音とあなたのための支援
reference as the Scriptures as Authority
権威としての聖書としての言及
so yeah so I've had those instances
そうそう私はそれらのインスタンスを持っていた
where where people have rejected what
どこで人々は何を拒絶したのか
I've said about the scriptures and about
私は聖書についてとについて述べた
about the gospel but when I've
福音について
referenced authority and given them
参照された権限とそれらに与えられた
evidence why I believe the conversation
会話を信じる理由
has changed so that's why because
変わったのでそれが理由です
suddenly it has a different undertone to
突然それは別の基底を持っています
it that there is some weight to what
何に重きがあるのか
you're saying and well and I think a lot
あなたが言っていることとよく、私はたくさん思う
of people have it's just hearsay and I
人々の中にはそれだけで伝聞があり、私は
know this for myself before I was a
私がされる前に私自身のためにこれを知っている
Christian I I just believe what I'd
クリスチャン2世は私がしたいことをただ信じる
heard other people say what the
他の人が何を言うのを聞いた
scriptures that they
その聖典
or you know this you know they were
または、これを 知っているあなた は彼らがいた ことを 知っています
written by men and their you know that
男性によって書かれ、 彼らはあなたが 知っている
they're not you know they just they
彼らはあなたではない彼らは彼らだけを知っている
can't possibly be the words of God and
おそらく神の言葉にはなれない
and all these things that you just write
そして、あなたが書いたこれらすべてのこと
them off and and you know nobody can
あなたは誰もできないことを知っています
know no one can know the truth and so I
誰も真実を知ることができないことを知っているので、私は
just regurgitate these things that I had
私が持っていたこれらの事をただ逆流させる
heard and I never took the time to
聞いて、私は時間をかけなかった
investigate and when I came to the Lord
調べて、私が 主 に来た時
he put upon my heart to study the
彼は私の心を勉強するために置いた
scriptures and he's revealed amazing
聖典と彼は驚くべきことを明らかにした
depths of truth and just a fantastic
真実の深さとただ素晴らしい
evidence now and that scholars for the
今証拠とそのための学者
last 50 years it just it's there and the
過去50年間で、
evidence is on our side and I think we
証拠は私たちの側にあり、私たちは私たちが考える
need to know that and I think it's it's
それを知っておく必要があります
important gods gone to those Lakes to
重要な神々はそれらの湖に行きました
show us mm-hmm well I remember as a kid
私は子供の頃覚えています
before we came to Christ because you
私たちがキリストに来る前に
came to Christ when you were in your 40s
40代のときにキリストに来た
mmhmm yeah so I was in my teens and I
mmhmmええ、だから私は私の10代にいたと私は
remember even before that your
その前でも覚えている
personality was always you know very
性格はいつもあなたが知っていた
kind of scientific and logical in their
科学的で論理的な
house there's explanations for things we
私たちのことについての説明があります
would have conversations at the dinner
夕食時に会話をする
table and I would ask dad you know how's
テーブルと私はあなたがどのように知っているお父さんに尋ねるだろう
the toilet work and does how does all
トイレの仕事とやり方
these things happen and why can I why is
これらのことが起こります、そしてなぜ私はなぜできますか
that true and dad would always indulge
その真実とお父さんはいつもふける
me and explain things and there was
私と物事を説明するとあった
always a reason actually it was more of
常に理由は実際にそれがもっとだった
a tactic to avoid going to bed as a kid
子供のように寝るのを避けるための戦術
but but I I can appreciate that you know
しかし、IIはあなたが知っていることを理解することができます
for people who want to have a solid
しっかりしたい人のために
understanding and what they believe and
理解と彼らが信じるもの
make sure it's not riddled with holes
穴があいていないことを確認してください
God has provided enough evidence or that
神は十分な証拠を提供した
that's me and we can know that the Bible
それは私です、そして私達はそれが聖書であることを知ることができます
is true and what we are reading is true
本当であり、私達が読んでいるものは本当です
well last week when we had Carmen on the
先週、 カルメンを
program she was sharing how with her
彼女が彼女とどのように共有していたか
mental illness she would have lies in
彼女が抱えるであろう精神病
her head that she knew were not true
彼女が知っていた彼女の頭は真実ではなかった
about who she was and whether she was
彼女が誰だったのか
going to heaven or hell and and she
天国か地獄へ行くそして彼女
would combat those lies with Scripture
それらの嘘を 聖書 と戦う
because she knew that it was true and
彼女はそれが本当であることを知っていたので
she started to do a lot of research and
彼女は多くの研究を行うために開始 し、
apologetics and gain a greater
謝罪し、より多くを得る
understanding about why the Bible why we
なぜ聖書はなぜ私たちを理解するのか
can put our trust in the Bible and that
聖書に信頼を置くことができます
helps solidify in her mind that yes god
彼女の心の中でそうであることを固めるのを助ける
loves me that yes he has a plan for my
はい、彼は私のための計画を持っていることを私を愛している
life he does care for me and i am going
人生彼は私の世話をしていると私は行きます
to heaven when I die it's because she
私が死ぬときは天国 に
knew that was true she is able to combat
彼女が戦うことができるというのは本当だったことを知っていた
those lives in her mind and to today and
それらは彼女の心の中でそして今日までそして
up to today stay strong in that so I
今日に至るまでそのことに強く留まるので、私は
think it's really interesting and
本当に面白いと思います
perfect timing that we're talking about
私たちが話していることを完璧なタイミング
this right after addressing mental
これは 精神的な演説の直後に
illness and Christianity so yeah yeah
病気とキリスト教
and I mean I think of the Bible Sunday
聖書の日曜日について考える
School songs jesus loves me this I know
学校の歌イエスは私が知っているこれを私を愛している
for the Bible tells me so well if if
聖書のためならばならばとてもよく言われます
that's it then I want to know that it's
それはそれからそれは私がそれであることを知りたいのです
true yes so where do you usually start
本当そうそうあなた は通常 どこ から始め ますか
dad I know that you have often had these
お父さん私はあなたがこれらをよく持っていたことを知っています
conversations with young people about
若者との会話について
why they can trust the Bible so where do
なぜ彼らは聖書を信じることができるのですか。
you even begin well I and I've had these
あなたも私から始めた
conversations with people I've met at my
私が出会った人との会話
work and been sharing my faith and
私の信仰を共有してきました
normally where I go is just it just
通常私が行くところはただそれだけです
briefly to ask them questions of what do
簡単に彼らに何をするかの質問をする
they know anything about the Bible do
彼らは聖書について何でも知っています
they understand how it has come together
彼らはそれがどのように結び付いたかを理解しています
I was compiled that there's an old and a
私は古いものと
new testament and when those books were
新約聖書とその時代の本
written the time frames when they're
彼らがいるときに時間枠を書いた
written so we have an old testament that
書かれているので、私たちには古い遺言があります。
all of there's 37 books in the Old
Oldには37冊の本があります
Testament that were 39 books in the Old
旧約39冊の遺言
Testament they were written hundreds of
彼らは何百もの書かれた遺言
years before Jesus I mean the last book
イエスの何年も前に私は最後の本を意味します
of the Old Testament is 400 years before
旧約聖書の400年前に
the birth of Christ and so all those
キリストの誕生、そしてすべての人々
books in the Old Testament of a time
時間 の旧約聖書の本
period between 1100 1500 years before
1100〜1500年前の期間
Christ to 400 years before Christ so we
キリストの400年前のキリスト
had this eleven hundred years of these
この1100年の間
books of these 39 books and then we have
これら39冊の本のうち、
the new testament to 27 books which were
27冊の新約聖書
written during and and just after the
間と直後に書かれた
death of christ and so we have
キリストの死、 そして 私たちは
essentially the Old Testament written
本質的に書かれた旧約聖書
over all these this time span over
この期間全体にわたって
almost of years and then the New
ほぼ何年も経ってから新しい
Testament written over basically one
基本的に一つの上に書かれた遺言
lifetime normal so to understand how the
生涯正常なので、どのように理解するために
book is compiled and then the only one
本はコンパイルされ、それから唯一の本
that says okay so all these books are in
それは大丈夫と言うので、 これら すべて の本は
the Old Testament one of the reference
旧約聖書の参照の1つ
they look at the book of the book itself
彼らはその本自体の本を見ます
why I why it's an authority we see all
なぜ私はそれが私たち全員に見られる権威だから
these old these books in the Old
これらの古いこれらの本
Testament written before Jesus was born
イエスが生まれる前に書かれた遺言
but then we have
しかしそれから
one scripture I go to very often and
1つの聖書私は非常に頻繁に行くと、
it's just you remember the one scripture
ただ一つの聖句を覚えているだけです
so you just have to explain when the
だからあなたはただいつ説明しなければなりません
books were written the Old Testament is
本は旧約聖書が書かれています
written hundreds of years before Christ
キリストの何百年も前に書かれた
that's that's basically the what I say
それが基本的に私が言うことです
and then I go to one scripture verse to
それから私は聖書の一節に行きます。
start it off I said we you know all you
始めましょう私たちはあなたがあなたをすべて知っていると言いました
have to do is read john 5 39 where Jesus
する必要がありますジョン5 39ここでイエスは読む
says speaking to the Pharisees with the
とパリサイ人と話す
lawkeepers if his time in Judea he said
弁護士はユダヤで彼の時間なら彼は言った場合
he says you search the Scriptures for in
彼はあなたが聖書の中を探す
them you think you find eternal life but
彼らはあなたが永遠の命を見つけると思いますが
these are the scriptures that testify
これらは証する聖文です
about me now the thing that you have to
私について今あなたがしなければならないこと
understand is that's recorded what Jesus
それはイエス様が記録されているということです
said but when he said it the New
と言ったが、彼がそれを言ったとき、新しい
Testament wasn't in existence you're
遺言は存在していませんでした
reading it from John chapter 5 verse 39
ヨハネ5章39節からそれを読む
which was written by the Apostle John
これは使徒ヨハネによって書かれました
which recorded the life death and
これは生死と
resurrection of Jesus Christ it's one of
イエス・キリストの復活
the four Gospels the first four books of
四福音書の最初の四冊
the New Testament right but Jesus is
新約聖書は正しいがイエスは
referencing the scriptures and what
聖典を参照すること
scriptures are he referenced is he
彼が言及している聖典は彼です
referencing well he's not referencing
よく参照しているのではない
the New Testament he's referencing the
彼が参照している新約聖書
Old Testament what he's saying the
旧約聖書、彼が言っていること
verses in the Old Testament are actually
旧約聖書の詩は実際には
about me he is actually saying he's
私について彼は実際に彼が言っているのです。
making an incredible claim and all you
信じられないほどの主張をし、あなた方全員
have to do at my challenge to people
私の挑戦 を人々に しなければならない
when I when I say this to mrs. he's
私がこれを夫人に言うとき。彼は
either correct or he isn't the Old
正しいか彼は古くない
Testament which was written before he
彼の前に書かれた遺言
was born is either about him or it isn't
生まれたのは彼のことではないか
right and all you have to do is
正しいそしてあなたがしなければならないのはただ
investigate yourself the onus now is
自分の責任を今調査する
back on them I've done their
彼らに戻ってやった
investigation and then I you know you
捜査そしてそれから私はあなたが知っている
know you know i'll give them scriptural
私は彼らに聖書をあげる
references in the old testament but the
旧約聖書に は
entire Old Testament is a progressive
旧約聖書全体が進歩的です
revelation of what of God's plan of
神の計画の何の啓示
salvation through Jesus Christ and then
イエス・キリストによる救い
that that promise is fulfilled in his
その約束は彼の内に成し遂げられること
birth and his life and his death in his
彼の誕生と彼の人生と彼の死
resurrection but it's for told thousands
復活しかしそれは数千人に言われたためです
of years before the events and Jesus is
出来事とイエスの前に
pointing us back there he's making that
彼がそれを作っているのです
claim and all we have to do is challenge
主張し、私たちがしなければならないのは挑戦だけです
him on that clan is he correct if he's
彼の一族の彼は彼が正しいなら彼は正しいです
not right forget the whole thing but if
全部を 忘れて は いけません が
he is correct what are the implications
彼は正しいです 意味 は何 ですか
the implications are that he's God and
その意味は、彼が神であり、
why why is that because you jump to that
なぜあなたはそれにジャンプするので
I jump to that because how
どのようので 、私はそれにジャンプ
how can someone have their life for told
どのようにして誰かに命を与えることができるのか
before they come into to be to be born
彼らが生まれる前に
and so he is eternal he is God incarnate
そして彼は永遠であり、彼は神の化身です
in flesh and that's but we see a
肉の中には
progressive revelation of God and His
神と彼の進歩的な啓示
plan and it's fulfilled in Christ and
計画し、それはキリストにおいて成就し、そして
God became flesh God became man and died
神は肉になった神は人になり死んだ
for us and that was the plan right
私たちにとって、それは正しい計画でした
that's in fact that is that is the
それが実際にはそれが
entire theme of the Bible in fact and I
聖書の全テーマと私は
talked to people with the theme of the
をテーマにした人々との会話
Bible that they get they look at the new
聖書は、 彼らは新しいを見てもらう こと
and the old testament and all these
そして旧約聖書とこれらすべて
different books what's the theme there
別の本そこのテーマは何ですか
is a theme of the Bible and in fact the
聖書のテーマで、実際には
Scriptures tell us I don't have to
聖書は私にする必要はないと私たちに告げています
explain it I go right to the scriptures
私は 経典に 右に行くそれを説明
to let the Bible explain itself and the
聖書に自分自身と
theme of the Bible is Jesus Christ for
聖書のテーマはイエス・キリストです
we looking in second Timothy in the New
私達は新しいの2番目のティモシーで探しています
Testament chapter 3 verse 15 were Paul
聖書第3章15節はパウロでした
writing to his protege timothy paul is
彼のプロテージチモシーポールに書くことです
about to be to be killed he was he was
殺されようとしていた彼は彼だった
put to death and he's a it's the last
死に、彼はそれが最後だ
letter he ever wrote so it carries a lot
彼が今まで書いた手紙なのでそれはたくさんの
of weight he talks about the most
彼は最も体重について語っています。
important things and he writes to
重要なことと彼はに書き込みます
Timothy he says he says Timothy you know
ティモシー彼は言う彼は彼が言うティモシーあなたが知っている
you knowing the Holy Scriptures he says
あなたは彼が言う聖書を知っています
which are able to make you wise unto
あなたを賢くすることができる
salvation in Christ through faith in
信仰によるキリストへの救い
Jesus Christ so the Old Testament in the
イエス・キリストそうで旧約
Bible the scriptures are are the purpose
聖書は聖書が 目的である
of the Bible is to make us wise unto
聖書の意味は、私たちを賢くすることです。
salvation through faith in Jesus Christ
イエス・キリストを信じる信仰による救い
again Paul is not referencing the New
再びポールはニューを参照していません
Testament which which gives us the talks
話をしてくれる遺言
about the fulfillment of those Old
それらの昔の成就について
Testament Scriptures he's talking about
彼が話している聖書の経典
the Old Testament he's talking about
彼が話している旧約聖書
those old testament scriptures were
これらの旧約聖書の聖句は
written before Christ was born that make
キリストが生まれる前に書かれた
you wise unto salvation that say Jesus
あなたイエスと言う救い賢明
is coming he's going to be the one that
来ている彼はその こと に なるだろう
points to the very reality that that was
それがあるという現実を指し示しています
fulfilled in Christ and so there's no
キリストの中で成就したので、ない
scholars that would argue about the
について議論する学者
dating of the writing of the Old
オールドの執筆のデート
Testament books and the end and the
遺書と終わりと
earliest one to the birth of Christ is
キリストの誕生の最も早い時期は
some 400 years before his birth so how
彼の誕生の約400年前に
did how did they verify that oh there's
どうやって彼らはあああることを確認しましたか
no scholar there's no academic scholar
学者はいません学術的な学者はいません
there's nobody that would argue with
と主張するだろう誰もがありません
that now that's that's a settled factor
それが今では解決した要因です
the writing of these scriptures is the
これらの聖書の執筆は
dating is
デートは
there's no dispute there you can you can
あなたがすることができますそこに紛争はありません
take that and look at that yourself
それを取って自分で 見て ください
there's there's no question when these
これらはいつでも問題ありません
when they were written now the question
彼らが今書かれたとき、質問
that you have to satisfy is is is Jesus
あなたはイエスですされて満足している こと
and is Paul when he writes the second
そして彼が第二を書いた時、パウロです
timid in second Timothy is he correct is
第二 テモテで臆病なのは正しい
the Bible the Old Testament and the New
聖書旧約聖書と新
Testament is it about Jesus Christ and
遺言はイエス・キリストについてです
the redemption that we have through him
私たちが彼を通して持っている償還
and the reality is it is and it's
そして現実はそれであり 、それ は
fantastic the way of God has revealed
素晴らしい神の道が明らかにされた
that through progressive revelation over
進歩的な啓示を通して
time and through his word written by
時間によってそして彼によって書かれた言葉を通して
many different people penned by
多くの人が
different people but it is inspired by
さまざまな人々が、それはに触発されています
him and so by the Holy Spirit and so
聖霊によって、そして彼によって
it's amazing and that i put the
それは素晴らしいことだと私は
challenge back in in other people's
他の人の中に戻って挑戦する
hands now the thing you have to remember
今手を覚える必要があるもの
is this is not an intellectual exercise
これは知的な運動ではないですか
the reality is is that we come to Christ
現実は私たちがキリストに来るということです。
through the Spirit of God leads us but
神の御霊を通して私たちを導きますが
the evidence points us in the right
証拠は私たちを右に向ける
direction right it opens up our minds
正しい方向それは私たちの心を開きます
you know there's that there's a saying
ことわざ があるのがわかります
I've heard before if yeah yeah if the
前に聞いたことが ある
mind the heart cannot rejoice what the
心が喜ぶことはできません
mind cannot reconcile you know so it
心はあなたが知っているのでそれを調整することはできません。
there has to be reason and it has to be
理性があるに違いないし
evidence and one of the great scriptures
証拠と聖典の一つ
about that is in Hebrews chapter 11
それについてはヘブライ語の第11章にあります
verse 1 you know the verse mm-hmm it
1節あなたはmm-hmmそれを知っています
says what would the faith is it
信仰とは何か
describes to us what our faith is and
私たちの信仰とは何か
this is where people think our faith is
人々が私たちの信仰は
blind or we follow we follow just a hope
盲目か私たちが従う私たちはただの希望に従う
that has no evidence and the interesting
それは証拠がなく、 興味深い
thing is about Scripture it even tells
物事は聖書についてでさえそれが 言う
us what evident what what faith is now
私たちは何を明らかにしているのか
it says in Hebrews 11 1 it says now
ヘブル人への手紙11 1
faith is the assurance of things hoped
信仰は望んでいることの保証です
for the evidence of things unseen so
目に見えないことの証拠のために
it's telling us that faith is based on
それは信仰が根拠に基づいていることを私たちに伝えています
evidence okay and so their needs if God
証拠は大丈夫なので、神なら彼らの必要性
the evidence has to be there to support
証拠は支持するためにそこになければならない
our faith our faith is not blind because
私たちの信仰私たちの信仰は盲目ではありません。
when i think of evidence i think is
証拠だと思うとき
something tangible something i can
具体的な何か私ができること
interact with like if you're doing an
あなたがやっているかのように対話する
experiment the evidence is there that
その証拠があることを実験する
you know that your hypothesis is correct
あなたはあなたの仮説が正しいことを知っています
well sure it's saying it's the evidence
確かにそれは証拠だと言っている
of things unseen so easy thing that
目に見えないほど簡単な こと
there's that
それがあります
physical evidence of an unseen there's
目に見えないものの物理的証拠
physical evidence to support the unseen
目に見えないことを裏付ける物理的証拠
the hope of our fulfillment in our and
私たちの達成の希望と
our eternal life in Christ the evidence
キリストにおける私たちの永遠の命証拠
that God has given us is there and it so
神が 私たち に 与えてくださったのはそこにあり、そうです
but the idea that our faith what is your
しかし、私たちの信仰があなたのものであるという考え
faith our faith is we have a blind faith
私たちの信仰は私たちが盲目の信仰を持っているということです
people to say it's just wishful thinking
言うだけの人はそれがただの希望的な思考です
but it's not in fact all of us live
しかし、実際に私たち全員が住んでいるわけではありません
every day in fact almost every moment in
実際には毎日ほとんど
faith in something if we don't have
私たちが 持っ ていないのなら何かへの信仰
faith anything we can't do anything okay
私たちは大丈夫 何もできない信仰何か
what do you mean well I mean by if if I
あなたはどういう意味ですか？
was to go up in this room and I wanted
この部屋に上がることだったし、私は欲しかった
to if I said if I turned that if I get
もし私がそうすれば私がそれを向けるなら私が言ったならば
up and turn that light switch on the
そのライトスイッチを上げて
light will come on now I believe that
光は、今私はと信じている上に来ます
now if i can say that as much as i want
今私は 私が欲しい だけそれを言うことができるなら
say i believe it but the reality of my
私はそれを信じますが、私の現実
faith will be expressed and proven when
信仰はいつ表現され証明されるでしょう。
i actually get up and go in turn the
私は実際に起きて、順番に行きます
light on now my faith is justified my
私の信仰は正当化される
belief is justified and my actions are
信念は正当化され、私の行動は
justified so the fit my faith is the
正当化されたので、私の信仰は
investment of myself into that which i
私はそれに私自身の投資
believe which i have good evidence get
良い証拠があると思う
out and take the steps towards faith is
信仰へのステップを踏み出す
an action it is moving in the direction
それが方向に動いている行動
of what your belief but you have good
あなたの信念だがあなたは善を持っている
reasons to believe in so there's
信じる理由があるので
evidence to support what what you
あなたが何をサポートしているかの証拠
believe in and your faith is your
あなたの信仰はあなたを信じる
movement in that direction okay that
その方向への動きは大丈夫です
makes sense yeah so so where can you
そう理にかなっているのでそうあなたはどこにできますか
point us to a scripture in the Old
私たちに古い聖書を指し示す
Testament that that you've often used to
あなたがよく使っ ていた ことの証
refer people to that show where Christ
キリストがどこにいるかを示すために人々にそのことを紹介する
is yes i would point people that very
はい、私は人々にそれを非常に指摘するだろう
simply so if you think of a conversation
あなたが会話を考えれば
now that you might have with someone
誰かと一緒にいるかもしれないので
about your faith and very quickly you
あなたの信仰について、そしてすぐにあなたのことについて
can reference explain the the dating of
のデートの説明を参照することができます
the old and new Testament that the bible
古いものと 新しい新約聖書バイブル
is divided into sections and the dating
セクションとデートに分かれています
of the books that did all the Old
すべての昔のことをした本のうち
Testaments written before the birth of
の誕生前に書かれた遺言
Jesus and then we look at the New
イエス様、それから私達は新しい人を見ます
Testament where it's recorded his life
それが彼の人生を記録した遺言
and his death and his resurrection and
そして彼の死と彼の復活
he we recorded what he has said and we
彼が言ったことを記録した
see in John chapter 5 verse 39 so that's
ヨハネの第5章39節で見てください。
the only scriptural reference you have
あなたが持っている唯一の聖書の参照
to remember that's one of them there's
覚えているそれはそれらの一つです
only a few you have to remember to go
ほんの少しだけあなたが行って覚えておく必要があります
through this john 5 39 okay and jesus
このジョン5 39を通して大丈夫とイエス・キリストを通して
makes the claim
主張する
and he's talking about the scriptures
そして彼は聖書について話しています
that he's talking to the Pharisees that
彼がパリサイ人と話していること
they searched the scriptures for eternal
彼らは聖書の中から永遠の聖書を探しました
life but these are the scriptures that
人生が、 これらは聖書です
testify about me and explained that he's
私について証言し、彼が
actually referencing the Old Testament
実際に旧約聖書を参照する
so that's one verse that you'd point
だからそれはあなたが指摘したいと思う一節です
people to that gets us looking at the
その人は見て私たちを取得します
Old Testament and so I the question to
旧約聖書と私は質問に
them Jesus is making this claim that the
彼らはイエスがこう主張しているのです。
Old Testament written hundreds of years
何百年もの間書かれた旧約聖書
before his birth is about him right all
彼の誕生の前に彼について
they have to do is see if it's true or
彼らがしなければならないのは、それが本当かどうかを見ることです。
not do they do the the investigation
彼らは調査をしません
themselves and so where do you recommend
彼ら自身そしてだからあなたはどこをお勧めしますか
like how do you even start some people i
どのようにあなたは私も何 人 かの 人々を 始めますか？
don't know maybe some of you haven't
たぶんあなたの何人かは知らない
even really opened the Bible or maybe
本当に聖書を開いたとしても
you've done the old okay open it and
あなたは古いそれを開いて大丈夫をやった
read wherever it folds open to so how do
それが開く よう に折り畳まれるところはどこでも読む
you even get started jen and i have
あなたもjenを始め、私は持っています
talked in previous episodes about how we
前のエピソードで私たちがどのようにして話したか
actually read the Bible every day and
実際に毎日聖書を読み、
how God speaks to us through that but to
それを通して、神はどのように私たちに語られているのでしょう。
really do an in-depth study and learn
本当に綿密な勉強をして学びなさい
about the authority of the scripture
聖書の権威について
where should we well let's I think we
私たちはどこに私たちはよく考えましょう
should stay focused on this is an
これに 集中し続けるべきです
apologetic moment I'm explaining so what
謝罪の瞬間私は説明しているので何を
do you mean minute so you're you have an
あなたは分を意味するのですか？
opportunity now to give evidence for the
の証拠を与えるために今機会
authority of the scripture and you're
聖書の権威とあなたは
having a conversation you're sharing
あなたが共有して いる会話 をする
your faith and people are questioning
あなたの信仰と人々は質問しています
your faith yeah and the authority of the
あなたの信仰とその権威
Bible which you keep referencing to and
あなたが参照し続ける聖書と
this is a quick way by referencing john
これはjohnを参照することによる簡単な方法です。
5 39 giving them a quick explanation of
5 39
how the Bible is compiled with old and
聖書はどのようにoldと
new Testament and the dating of the
新約聖書とのデート
books reference john 5 39 jesus's claim
書籍の参照ジョン5 39 イエスの主張
explained that he's referenced in the
彼はで言及されていると説明した
old testament and that posed the
旧約聖書とそれが提起
question to them is he correct because
彼らへの質問は彼が正しいからです
if he's not you can write the whole
彼がそうでなければあなたは全体を書くことができます
thing off but if he is correct then
問題はありませんが、彼が正しい場合は
there's implications and the
影響があります
implications are that he's God he is who
その意味は、彼が神で あるということです。
he says he is and so you put that put
彼は彼がそうであると言うので、あなたはそのプットを入れます
the responsibility to investigate it
それを調査する責任
back in their lap because if they want
彼らが望むのであれば
to write it off there you've given them
それを書き留めるためにあなたは それら を与え ました
some evidence you've given you know I'm
あなたがあなたに与えたいくつかの証拠は私が知っている
not afraid for them to go and look
見に行くのを恐れてはいけません
because I know they're going to find the
私は、彼らが見つけるつもりだ知っているので、
truth I'm in fact I want to encourage
真実私は実際に私は励ましたいです
them to do so right but I'm putting it
彼らはそうするために正しいが、私はそれを入れている
back in them if they want to just you
彼らはあなただけにしたい場合はそれらに戻って
know criticize without evidence or just
証拠なしで批判する
you
君は
be their opinion well that's fine but I
彼らの意見でも大丈夫だけど私は
need evidence and if they're evidence if
証拠が必要であり、 それらが証拠である場合
the evidence that i'm suggesting is
私が示唆している証拠は
greater and stands up we're putting it
もっと大きくて立ち上がる
on the table basically say okay well
テーブルの上に基本的に 大丈夫と 言う
let's let's just see what the truth is
真実は何かを見てみましょう
and and so i would give them that give
そして私 は彼らに
them that challenge and then i would ask
彼らは挑戦し、それから私は尋ねるだろう
them okay if you want to see and there's
あなたが見たいのなら彼らは大丈夫だし
a couple of reference that I often give
私がよく与える参考文献
I give them I tell them that this book
私は彼らにこの本を伝えます
of psalms was written a thousand years
詩篇は千年間書かれた
before Jesus by King David most of it
その大部分はダビデ王によるイエスの前に
and then I reference Isaiah 53 and so I
それから私はイザヤ書第53号を参照して
just say these two scripts these two so
これら二つのスクリプトをこれら二つのように言うだけです。
go to the Psalms Psalm 22 ok and Isaiah
詩編22編okとイザヤ書に行きます
53 okay and so that's it they can do all
53 大丈夫です、 それですべてができるのです
that this whole thing in a few moments
しばらくするとこのこと全部
10 minutes of looking at the Bible and
聖書を見て10分
now they understand the dating of the
今、彼らはの出会い系を理解しています
writing and they look at the evidence of
書いて、彼らはの証拠を見ます
the writing what it's saying and
それは言って何を書いて、
hopefully they're going to come back and
うまくいけば、彼らは戻ってくるだろうと
it has some more question can have
もう少し質問があるかもしれません
another discussion so what now I've
今私がきたので、どのような別の議論
spoken to people about those verses
それらの聖句について人々に話された
before and sometimes got the response
前にそして時々応答を得ました
that well you know how do I actually
それであなたは私が実際にどのように知っているか
know that the Book of Isaiah was written
イザヤ書が書かれたことを知っている
so many years before Christ how do we
キリストの何年も前に
know that well that's a simple scholarly
これは単純な学術的なことです
I mean that the writings that in fact
私はその文章が実際に
you could guy like me in fact you can
あなたは私と同じように男になることができます
reference the Dead Sea Scrolls okay
死海の巻物は大丈夫
because the Dead Sea Scrolls you have
死海の巻物があるから
the entire book of Isaiah recorded and
イザヤ書全体の記録と
the dating of the Dead Sea Scrolls is is
死海の巻物の年代は
not in dispute and it's 150 to 200 years
紛争ではなく、150年から200年
before Christ so there you have it and
キリストの前にあなたはそれを持っています
it the great things about dead sea
それは死海の素晴らしいところです
scrolls is that matches the the Book of
巻物はBook of Bookに一致する
Isaiah that we have now the recording
イザヤが今録音していること
this is that's the great thing nothing's
これは素晴らしいことだ何もない
changed really yes and so and so there
本当にそう変化した
you have it and we have an old copy
あなたはそれを持っていて、私たちは古いコピーを持っています
that's hundreds of years before Christ
キリストの何百年も前
right which matches the copy that you're
あなたが持っているコピーと一致する権利
reading in your Bible now so therefore
今あなたの聖書を読むので
that gives it its is dating authority
それはそれがデート権であることをそれに与えます
okay okay so that that's a quick and
大丈夫大丈夫ですので、それは迅速であり、
people have heard of the Dead Sea
人々は死海のことを聞いたことがある
Scrolls may not know what they are when
スクロールは、 彼らがするときが何であるかを知らないかもしれません
you reference them they can quickly
あなたはそれらを素早く参照することができます
google them and find out yeah what they
それらをグーグルし、ええ彼らが何を知っている
are yeah and see that they're the Book
ええと彼らは本であることを参照してください
of Isaiah actually they were in the war
イザヤの人々は実際に戦争にあった
on terror museum a couple of years ago
数年前のテロ博物館に
people so but the dating of the old
人々はそうだが、 老人のデート
testament is not in a dispute the books
遺言 は本をめぐる論争ではない
that are there so it is when i go to
それはそこにあるので私が行くとき
find that you know you know you say
あなたが言うことを知っていることを知っていることを見つけます
there's no scholar that would dispute
論争する学者はいない
that now but i could just say that but
それは今でもしかし私はそれを言うことができましたが
how do i find out that well again you
どのように私はあなたにそれをもう一度よく見つけるのですか
can google the days of the Old Testament
旧約聖書の時代をグーグルすることができます
quickly I mean any any encyclopedia
すぐに私は任意の百科事典を意味する
about the Old Testament books will give
旧約聖書についての本は与えるでしょう
you the dating of the writing and they
あなたは執筆のデートと彼ら
don't have to be Christians collect
クリスチャンが集まる必要はありません
repeated it could be you know secular
それはあなたが世俗的な知っているかもしれない繰り返し
encyclopedia but the books of the Old
百科事典だが昔の本
Testament right there's no question
遺言正しい質問はありません
about the dating anymore and one thing I
もうデートについてのことと私が一つのこと
find interesting about the Old Testament
旧約聖書について興味深い発見
is that the books often refer to like
本はしばしばのように参照するということです
the political scenario of the time and
当時の政治シナリオと
like who was routing in Israel and that
誰がイスラエルを旅していたかのように
is consistent with historical documents
歴史的文書と一致している
well and we we're making the claim that
私たちはその主張をしている
this is the word of God so it only
これは神の言葉なのでそれだけです
stands the reason that God got his
神が彼を得た理由
history right yeah I would hope so okay
歴史正しいそうだね
and so we can stand in comfort and again
そして私達は慰めにそしてまた立つことができる
that's another reason you can then go
それはあなたがその後行くことができるもう一つの理由です
into coma see I don't care which way you
昏睡状態に私はどの ようにあなたを 気にしない参照してください
come at the Bible whether it's from the
聖書に来ているかどうか
prophetic side from the scientific side
科学的側面からの予言的側面
from a historical side from you know it
あなたから歴史的な側面からそれを知っています
answers the big questions of life it has
人生の大きな問題に答える
a unity of all of these 66 excusing 66
66を除く66のすべての団結
books in the Bible that are tied
縛られている聖書の本
together over although the written over
書かれたが一緒に
a period of fifteen hundred years are
1500年の期間があります
tied together there's a unity in these
一緒に結ばれてこれらの団結がある
books and they present a story and a
本と彼らは物語と
plan of God that is just incredible it's
信じられないほど神の計画
breathtaking when you consider all the
あなたがすべてを考えるとき息をのむような
time it took and the different people
所要時間とさまざまな人々
that penned these books and different
それはこれらの本と別の
circumstances and yet they're tied
状況とそれでも縛られている
together there's a there's a cohesion
一緒に結束がある
because the author is the Holy Spirit
作者は 聖霊だからです
and so it's just amazing we see the
そしてそれは我々が見ているだけで素晴らしいです
museum and do you remember like after
美術館や、あとでのように覚えていますか
you became a Christian where that light
あなたはクリスチャンになりました
bulb kind of came on where you realized
気づいたところに電球がやってきた
the Bible was the Word of God yes and
聖書は神のことばでした
how did that happen it was doing a
それはどうやってそれがやっていたのですか
similar study like that I'm listening to
私が聞いているのと同じような研究
there's fantastic scholars that we have
私たちが持っている素晴らしい学者がいます
nowadays and who would you recommend
今日そしてあなたは誰を推薦しますか
from a apologetic standpoint whether you
謝罪の観点から
want to look at technical things like
のような技術的なものを見たい
dating and stuff like that if you want
あなたが望むならデートやそのようなもの
to look at those types of things or you
そのような種類のものや あなたを見るために
want to look at
見たい
making apologetics on a moral basis for
の道徳的根拠に基づいて謝罪をする
the Bible or is it you know the basis of
聖書かそれがあなたが基礎を知っているか？
the writings and how do they relate to
文章とそれらはどのように関連していますか
the reality that we live in they do and
私たちが住んでいる現実 はそうです
they stand up like nothing else and so
彼らは他の何もないように立ち上がるので
the apologetic approach that you're
あなたがしている謝罪のアプローチ
taking whatever subject you're looking
あなたが探しているものは何でも取る
at there are some great authors out
何人かの素晴らしい作家がいます
there right now Ravi Zacharias from it
そこから今そこにRavi Zacharias
from the from the point perspective of
の視点から
of presenting the scriptures as as the
聖文を
Word of God from a moralistic and and
道徳からの神のことばと
and just lining up with the reality that
現実と並んで
we live in right I would recommend from
私達は私がから推薦する正しい住む
technical standpoint Josh McDowell has a
技術的な観点Josh McDowellは、
wonderful book the evidence is its
素晴らしい本の証拠はそれです
evidence that's worth knowing that
知っ ておく価値のある証拠
demand everything to the man's a very
男のものにすべてを要求する
Carmen actually also recommended that
カルメンは実際にもそれをお勧めします
one to me after our discussion last week
先週の議論の後に私に一つ
so and actually if you want to be able
そうそして実際にあなたができるようにしたいのなら
to get any of those resources you can go
あなたが行くことができるこれらのリソースのいずれかを得るために
to our website new everyday TV and click
私たちのウェブサイトの新しい毎日のテレビにクリックして
our partners page and you can go to
私たちのパートナーページとあなたはに行くことができます
Amazon through there and get resources
そこを通ってAmazonがリソースを手に入れる
from any of those authors through our
私たちを通してこれらの作家のいずれかから
website so Wow dad it's a great start
Webサイトなので、お父さんはすごいスタートです
and I know that we've had so many
そして私達は私達がとても たくさん 持っていたことを知っています
discussions about this in the past and
これに関する過去の議論
I've always just so appreciated so thank
いつも感謝しています
you so much for coming and I hope that
来てくれてありがとう。
you will come on again maybe next week
来週もまた来るだろう
okay thanks so much thanks for tuning in
大丈夫おかげでチューニングに感謝します
to new every day dad would you just pray
新しい毎日パパに祈るだけですか
as we close sure that'd be great
私たちはそれが素晴らしいことだと確信して閉じる
Heavenly Father we give you thanks that
天のお父様、ありがとうございます
you are mindful of us who are a way that
あなたは私たちを意識しています。
you are mindful us pilot but you love us
あなたは私たちパイロットを意識していますが、あなたは私たちを愛しています
and you pour out your grace upon us
そしてあなたは私たちにあなたの恵みを注ぎます
father you've proven yourself you've
お父さん証明した
shown us and you say in your word father
私たちを見せて、あなたはあなたの言葉で父と言う
that i will i will show you who i am and
私は私が誰だかを紹介しますということと、
prove my word by i will show you these
私の言葉を証明する私はあなたにこれらを表示します
things that they will become true your
彼らが本当になること
word is truth lord and so i'll tell you
言葉は真実の主 です ので、私はあなたに 言うよ
things you say you can tell us things
あなたが言うものあなたは私たちにものを伝えることができる
before they happen and they do
彼らが起こる前に、彼らはする
father your word lines up and so father
あなたの言葉が並ぶ父親
we thank you and that you've taken the
ありがとうございます。
time you've given us the evidence father
証拠の父親を私たちに与えた時
you've given us it's reasonable the
あなたは私たちに与えた
evidence that you've given us father
あなたが私たちに父親を与えたという証拠
points us to who you are and I pray that
あなたが誰であるかを私たちに指摘し、私はそれを祈ります
we would follow that evidence if we're
私たちがいるならば、私たちはその証拠に従うでしょう
searching that those that are searching
探しているものを探している
father would find you they would be
父親はあなたが彼らになるだろうあなたを見つけるだろう
pointed in your direction by the
あなたの方向を
evidence and they've followed where it
証拠と 彼らはそれがどこでそれに従った
leads and by your grace father leads us
導き、 あなたの恵みによって私たちを導きます
to the foot of the cross the salvation
十字架のふもとに救い
in Jesus Christ we give you thanks Lord
イエス・キリストにおいて、私たちはあなたに感謝します
in his precious name amen amen thanks
彼の貴重な名前で
again and thank you we hope you'll tune
もう一度、ありがとうございます
in next week for episode 22 have a great
来週のエピソード22には素晴らしい
week
週間
you
君は